A Guide to the JMU Women's Club Records, 1977-2013: UA 0035
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
JMU Women's Club Records,
1977-2013
Special Collections, James Madison University
JMU Woman's Club (1977-2006)
UA 0035
1.75 cubic feet; 6 boxes
The JMU Women's Club Records are comprised of newsletters, yearbooks, directories, papers, scrapbooks, media files and photographs that document the activities of the JMU Woman's Club, from 1977-2013.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Records were donated by Elizabeth Ihle on April 4, 1996. Scrapbooks were donated by Beverly Silver on November 28, 2016.
Administrative History
The JMU Women's Club, also called the JMU Woman's Club, was formed in 1977, as a continuation of the Faculty Wives' Sewing Circle (1947-1951), Faculty Wives' Club (1952-1967), and the Madison College Women's Club (1968-1976). Membership was open to JMU women faculty, administrators, staff and retirees, as well as wives of JMU faculty, administrators, staff and retirees. Their mission was to "build community spirit, promote friendship, and support projects that will benefit the University." The club is no longer active, though directories are printed through 2005. The Honorary Life Members, a JMU Women's Club interest group for retired club members, continued to meet through 2013. The JMU Women's Club administered the Edith Carrier Scholarship, available for children of JMU faculty members, and coordinated social gatherings and interest groups.
Scope and Content
The JMU Women's Club Records are comprised of newsletters, yearbooks, directories, papers, scrapbooks, media files, realia and photographs that document the activities of the JMU Woman's Club, from 1977-2013. Yearbooks and directories contain membership rosters, club officers, interest groups, recipients of the Ellen Chappell Award of Merit and the Edith Carrier Scholarship, past presidents and officers, and the club's constitution. The collection contains meeting minutes, administrative files, promotional materials and correspondence. Three scrapbooks contain photographs, programs and papers documenting the activities of the Honorary Life Members Interest Group. The collection also includes four t-shirts, and a banner used at JMU Women's Club events.
Arrangement
Items are arranged by subject matter. The scrapbooks remain bound in a flat box.
Separated Materials
Applications for the Edith Carrier Scholarship with personal and identifying information were removed from the collection and disposed.
Bibliography
"Women's Club Offers $1000 Scholarship." The Breeze. February 3, 2003. Accessed February 20, 2018. http://commons.lib.jmu.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1158&context=i20002009.
Index Terms
Subjects:
James Madison University -- History; James Madison University -- Faculty; Women in higher education -- History; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
Scrapbooks; Photographs; Letters (correspondence); Newsletters; Yearbooks; Membership lists; Constitutions; Programs (documents); Invitations; T-shirts; Banners; Directories; Floppy Discs; CD-ROMS
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Meeting Minutes, 1992-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Budget Reports, 1978-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Yearbooks and Directories, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Yearbooks and Directories, 1991-2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Administrative Files, 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Constitution and Bylaws, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, 1993-2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1977-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Memorandum, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ellen Chappell Award of Merit, 1984-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Edith Carrier Scholarship, 1990-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Membership Lists, 1977-2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Membership Forms, 1989-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Interest Groups, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Honorary Life Group, 1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Friendship Committee, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Newcomers Group, 1988-1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Website, 1999-2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Discount Card Business Agreements, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Promotional Material and Flyers, 1977-2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Events Planning Papers, 1986-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Events Planning Papers, 1993-2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Women's Club Letter Head, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- JMU Programs, 2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ephemera, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photographs and Negatives, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Digital Media, 2002-2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Four T-Shirts, undated (Box 4)
- Honorary LIfe Members Interest Group Scrapbook, 1987-2010 (Box OV1)
- Honorary LIfe Members Interest Group Scrapbook, 2012-2013 (Box OV1)
- Honorary LIfe Members Interest Group Scrapbook, 2011 (Box OV1)